Raúl Esteban Burró Cespedes

Email: rauleburro@gmail.com

Nationality: Paraguayan/Spanish

Profile

Software engineer with +3 years of experience developing backend apps and deploying on the cloud utilizing digital-ocean, GCP, docker, docker-compose, and Kubernetes. Fast learner and autodidact, proactive, and proficient.

Able to effectively collaborate as part of a productive team, providing reliable solutions to problems, and willing to create a comfortable work environment. I am excited to continue strengthening my career and increasing my skills.

Technologies

Django, Nodejs, Google Cloud Platform, Kubernetes, Docker, Digital Ocean, Git, Github, Jira.

Skills

- Making the right choice and having sound knowledge of our tools.
- Keep the code clean and able to adapt.
- Great problem solver.
- · Efficient trough optimization
- · Aim for success at the start.
- Self-evaluate along the way
- Full-cycle software development using Agile methodologies (SCRUM).

Experience

Frontend/Mobile Developer and SRE/DevOps

Bucksapp | Sep 2021 - Present

- I work maintaining the infrastructure on the Google Cloud Platform.
- Manage networks, VMS, load balancers, DNS, databases, Redis, and Cloud Run Apps on CGP
- I create new infrastructures using GKE, configure the monitoring using Prometheus and grafana, Service mesh using Linkerd, and Manage the environments for the infrastructure using Kustomize.
- Implementing DevOps using GitHub Actions, GitHub Super Linter, Testing Actions, and Continues Deployment build images on the pipeline.

Co-Founder

Bellbird | Jan 2020 - Present

- I founded this company in 2020 to develop technology solutions for our clients.
- My first client, PuntoFarma, is the most extensive pharmacy in Paraguay. I developed for then a
 mobile app using flutter. I connected their oracle backend using an intermediate backend written in
 node.js and deployed it on a server using docker and docker-compose. Today the app manages the
 traffic of +9k users per day.
- Implement infrastructure of all the apps with docker and docker-compose.
- Implement new infrastructure for the company using Kubernetes with Rancher.

- Implement monitoring with Prometheus and Grafana.
- Implement service mesh with Linkerd.
- Implement webhooks to connect GitLab with Discord chat for the pipelines.
- Implement CI/CD using Gitlab CI.
- In 2021, I hired more people for my team, and I started managing the company as a CEO and managing Team.
- In September of 2021, I saw the company could be auto administrate, and I decided to leave my position as a CEO to dedicate my time to work as a software engineer and DevOps engineer.
- I am still on the board, but I don't need to stay operative in the company.

Fullstack software engineer / Tech Lead

Softec SRL | Sep 2016 - Jan 2020

- I Start working with Django apps using javascript for the front and implementing testing using Selenium.
- In 2017, I started working on an Uber-like app called MUV with two Android apps, one for drivers and one for clients, and two apps IOS with swift. And a backend in laravel.
- I lead a team of 3 developers until the app's release in 2018.
- In 2018, after the app's release, my team started working on version 2 of the app MUV. We used React Native for the app, React for the front, and Node for the backend.
- After that, in 2019, I was promoted to Tech Lead of the company and started to manage four teams with different skills using Gitlab workflow.

FullStack Developer

Freelance | Jan 2014 - Sep 2016

• I started my professional life in 2012 as a freelancer doing some projects using Django as a whole stack framework, an app with Android framework, and many websites.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in computer science, Universidad Nacional de Asunción, San Lorenzo, Paraguay

Languages

- English (Intermediate)
- Spanish (Native)

Platforms

Linux, macOS, Windows